Man:
U.S. Military escort cdc team.
Requesting permission
to enter egyptian airspace.
Man ♪2: Permission granted.
Dr. Scott. on to the right.
Take a look.
Man ♪3: He's on approach.
Visibility... good.
Time to target... three minutes.
Roger that. 2-2-0.
Roger that. I see it.
Status... green.
Dr. Scott. prepare for landing.
Putting down close to...
20 feet.
10 feet.
And we're down.
Doctor. you've got five minutes.
This way.
There are 6.000 quarantined
in this camp.
We have 387 dead.
My staff is down to six!
I thought you were bringing
more doctors with you.
These are the latest
to come down with the virus.
Once the spots come.
they die in two days.
I'm sorry.
Slattery: Make sure those snowmobiles
go to starboard hangar "f"!
Chief spurling. chief lewis. we
are getting under way at 1300.
Let's pick up the pace. okay?!
Yeah. I know all about
the naval mountain warfare unit.
But I've never heard of a dog
setting foot on a destroyer.
This isn't just a dog.
This is admiral halsey.
And he's a mean operator.
Yeah? Well. so is the captain.
Rachel: You can just
put that down over there.
Be careful.
That's delicate equipment.
I take it
you're my new houseguest.
I'm commander chandler.
ship's captain.
Rachel scott.
I'm sorry we had to take over
your helicopter bay.
But it was the only space large
enough to accommodate our lab.
I got 217 men and women
on this ship.
Anything
I should be concerned about?
Oh. this?
Um. this is just so
we don't contaminate the work...
Not the other way around.
What exactly are you gonna
be studying up there?
Birds.
Birds?
We are virologists...
Tracking obscure microbes
in hard-to-get-to places.
Pretty boring stuff. actually.
We really do appreciate your
assistance. captain chandler.
We're here to serve.
Welcome aboard. doctor.
Jeter: Roger that. Red deck.
Bird's chocked and chained.
heading to the barn.
Damn. it's cold.
I can't feel my face.
Lieutenant granderson.
tell me...
Do I still have my face?
Yes. sir. though it looks like.
You could use some lip balm.
sir.
Should've taken
that desk job in miami.
It is cold!
Alisha: Captain's on the bridge!
X.O. Slattery.
Let's see if we can get
your frozen ass back to norfolk.
T.A.O.. bridge. Bridge. t.A.O.
Our helo just dropped a target
for our final missile test.
Target's five feet long.
two feet wide.
And in the icy water
has no heat signature.
Let's find it and kill it.
Woman: Scanning for target.
Scanning zone.
Man: Kill track 5205.
Target acquired.
Target acquired. Break.
Kill track 0845. aye.
Mss. kill track 0845.
Man: Missile ready to fire.
Missile clear. 2-2-0. 30.
30.000.
Boom. Siegle: Target
confirmed kill.
Good afternoon. nathan james.
This is the captain.
After four very challenging
months at the top of the world.
We have just passed
our final test.
And I'm proud to say
you did it with flying colors.
I'm asking the pentagon if
we can break radio silence today.
And make calls and e-mail.
Bravo zulu
to each and every one of you.
Enjoy your success.
'cause we're going home.
Gonna drop to 50 below.
Get them off the ice.
Jeter: Aye. sir.
Man: Dr. Scott. come in.
Dr. Scott. are you there?
Please respond.
Dr. Scott. come in.
You have got to be kidding me.
We're so close.
We need to make sure.
The isolate isn't contaminated.
We need more samples.
It's all right. rachel.
We can come back tomorrow.
Ma'am. we've been
trying to reach you.
C.O. Wants you back on the ship.
You can tell the captain
that I'll return when I'm ready.
It wasn't an invitation. ma'am.
Right now. Captain's orders.
Man: Landing check is complete.
Gear down and locked.
20 feet.
10 feet.
Wheels down.
We haul ass from here. we can
make it back for the series.
You don't really think
the cubs are still in it.
It's the weakest division
in baseball.
We were six games up
when we left.
Yeah. that was June.
And they're the cubs.
Captain chandler. you had no
right to pull me from my work.
I'm gonna go check on the.
uh... Yeah.
Those men are here
to support me.
You don't send them to bring me in.
Those men are sailors in the u.S. Navy.
And report directly to me. I
say when I am done and ready.
My work is vital here.
and I have finally found.
What I'm looking for! Doctor!
First of all.
thanks for checking in.
Think this is the first time
you said more than three words.
To me since we left norfolk.
Well. I am sorry that
I haven't had you over for tea.
You know. your attitude
was mildly charming.
Back in June in virginia.
but up here. at 50 below.
When none of us have talked
to our families in four months.
Not so charming.
Yeah. well. charm
wasn't exactly my pri...
Still talking.
Now. I think I've been
more than a gracious host...
Taxied you and your assistant
around the islands here.
So you could chase after
your ducks.
Arctic terns.
You need to wrap it up.
Our mission's done.
and we'll be heading back.
I'll take a rain check
on the tea.
Benzo. eat some fruit.
Oh!
Come on. mr. Chung. It's our
last night at the north pole.
Look. I know
you've got big plans.
But don't you ever get your head
out of that book?
Nope.
Okay.
Lieutenant.
Danny. whoa.
Don't do that.
Do what?
You know
what that smile does to me.
All's fair in love and war.
Yeah.
Kara... We'll be
home soon enough.
Rachel: Hello.
Are you reading me?
Come in.
No. I cannot wait.
This is dr. Rachel scott.
I need to speak to the national
security adviser right away.
You don't understand.
My mission is being compromised.
And I need more time
to collect samples.
We have a noisy channel.
I repeat.
Mission objectives achieved.
We are ready to come home. Over.
Man:
That's a negative. commander.
The mission has been extended.
Over.
Extended? Why?
Maintain radio silence
and current position.
Until you receive
further instructions.
Mason:
Transmission terminated. sir.
The hell is that woman doing?
Rachel: Quincy... I
think we've got it.
Danny: Sorry. man.
Did I wake you?
Doc told me to keep my distance.
The admiral's
scaring off the birds.
Sure it was the dog
and not your breath?
Whatever.
Man. we should've been
out of here days ago.
What the... Mason:
Aircraft in position.
Seven six
decimal three five north.
Zero five nine
decimal five eight east...
Captain. I have three...
make that five unknown aircraft.
Approaching. range 24 nautical
miles. approximately 80 knots.
Those are not ours. man.
No. They're russian.
Come on!
Quincy.
we have to save the samples!
Help me!
Leave the box! Let's go!
Rachel. leave the box!
Let's go! Right now!
Let's go! Come on!
Quincy!
Drop.
Aah!
Set general quarters. General
quarters. general quarters.
All hands.
man your battle stations.
Transit up and forward
starboard side.
Down and aft portside.
Unknown aircraft...
Man: T.A.O.. air.
New air contact 80234.
At 015 at 36.000 yards.
Inbound...
T.A.O..
surface manned and ready.
Deploy scat.
Ciws to a.A.W. Auto.
Hold fire on.
Aah!
Take him alive!
All engines ahead flank! Hard left rudder!
All engines ahead flank. aye!
Mason:
...United states naval warship.
Identify yourself
and alter your course.
Or you will be subject
to defensive actions. Over.
Evaluate as inbound missile.
Recommend launch chaff.
Brace for shock!
All hands. brace for shock.
Take 'em out.
Go to the 5 inch!
Surface. t.A.O..
kill track 5024.
Kara: Surface. aye.
Guns. kill track 5024.
Man: Guns. aye.
You okay?!
Clear! Come on.
Chandler: Where's dr. Scott?!
She's banged up pretty good.
Doc's looking at her
in hangar two.
What'd he say?
"The cure."
He wants the cure.
All our guys are accounted for.
We at war with the russians?
Get me fleet forces.
They don't answer. get me nmcc.
They don't answer.
get me secdef.
Supposed to be radio silent.
Not anymore.
I told you I'm fine.
Just hurry up.
Where's quincy?
I need my samples.
You don't get your samples.
Until you tell me
what's going on here.
You have no authority
over me... everybody out!
You need to hand that case
over to me right now.
We may have just gone to war
with russia.
And they were clearly after you.
No more secrets.
Tell me about the cure!
I can't say anything.
Until I speak to the national security... I
swear to god. I will throw this overboard!
I want answers!
You want answers?
Seven months ago. outside cairo.
there was an outbreak...
A virus of unknown origin.
Its genetic structure.
Was like nothing any of us
had ever seen.
It swept throughout the village.
Killing everyone
that it infected.
Egyptian officials claimed
the outbreak was contained.
But it wasn't.
Instead. it continued
to mutate and spread.
The cdc and the w.H.O.
Wanted to sample the virus.
From the victims
to create a vaccine.
But nothing worked.
It was my belief that we needed
to find the primordial strain.
Here in the arctic.
The birds.
They're just the carriers.
They pick up the virus
from the melting permafrost.
We finally found
their feeding ground.
So you have what you need
to stop this thing?
I won't know until we get it
back to the lab.
We're running out of time.
The virus back home
is moving quicker.
Than any of us
could've imagined.
How would you know that?
We've been radio silent
since we left norfolk.
Because I have my own sat phone.
We were at emcon so no one
would know our position!
We were at emcon
to protect my mission...
Not yours.
Orders came
from the white house.
Well. you led the russians
right to us.
And endangered my entire crew.
It was imperative
that I stay in contact.
With the labs back home
to keep them informed.
Of my progress.
I don't think you understand
what we're talking about here.
Enlighten me.
When we left norfolk.
The virus was at phase two.
Limited to small clusters
in asia and africa.
We are now at phase six...
Global pandemic.
80% of the world's population
is infected.
The world is sick.
captain chandler...
Very sick.
Are you telling me
the whole world is dying.
And they send two people
to save it?
It took weeks to convince the
government to even send me here.
Most of my colleagues
think that I'm insane.
Are you?
I told you... That
what's in that case...
Might be the only hope
that we have.
Captain. we have the president
of the United States.
On the vidcom.
I'm sorry
you had to find out this way.
Can I have my samples now?
Man: Stand by for the president.
Morning. commander.
Ma'am?
I know. The last you heard.
I was speaker of the house.
The president
died two months ago.
The vice president a week later.
What's left
of the federal government.
Is holed up
200 feet below the white house.
And communication
is getting spotty.
So we need to know now...
Does dr. Scott have what
she needs to make a vaccine?
She thinks so. ma'am.
We are sending you
the coordinates.
To a secure bio-lab
on the coast of north carolina.
Ma'am. we were just attacked
by the russians.
Russia no longer has
a functioning government.
From what we're hearing.
A breakaway force is operating
on its own authority.
We're trying to ascertain
all the facts.
Ma'am. our families...
how do we find out if...
I wish I could tell you.
captain.
Most of our population.
al... with our armed forces.
Is dying or dead.
We have no allies.
We have no enemies.
Just a world of sick.
desperate people.
Your ship was fortunate enough
to be out of the hot zone.
These past months.
If dr. Scott
has the makings of a cure.
You have to come home... Now.
Man: Supply chains
are completely broken.
Food is in short supply.
Hospitals...
Woman: ...Chinese government.
Have detonated the bomb
on its own people.
To stop the spread
of the deadly virus.
Woman ♪2: With possibly
half the world's population
Dead or dying. rumors that
the u.S. Is hoarding a vaccine.
Continue to swirl.
Man ♪2: Urban services
are completely overwhelmed.
In most cities.
entire power grids are down.
Making communication
next to impossible.
Man ♪3: People are asking.
"where is the government?"
The virus has no treatment.
no vaccine.
So this whole weapons test...
it was all just a cover.
And emcon alpha...
Keep us in the dark about
what was going on at home.
There's an unmanned refueling
station off the coast of France.
If we operate at trail shaft.
we should just make it.
How do we know
they have enough fuel.
To get us across the atlantic?
We don't.
What do we tell the crew?
Everything.
We tell them everything.
Captain?
Crew's assembled.
Ship's company. attention!
I have news... From home.
Mason: Any station this net.
This is nathan james
transmitting in the blind.
On fleetsat one. two. and three.
over.
Is anybody out there?
Due to widespread
system failure.
The number you are calling
cannot be reached.
This message
will not be updated.
Daddy!
Darien: I can't believe
I'm gonna go that long.
Without hearing your voice.
Ashley: We miss you. daddy.
Captain's on the bridge!
Sir. we're 50 miles
off the coast of europe.
And still no contact
with french naval command.
We've got extra watch
and guns at the ready.
Were you able to reach home?
No. sir.
I think only four people
got through to anyone.
And the news wasn't good.
Last time we made port
in France.
I promised my girlfriend.
We'd come back
and see paris together.
With everything. that's all
I keep thinking about.
Well. that's the stuff
that matters.
Jeter: X.O.'s on the bridge.
I got through to home.
My boy's gone.
Oh. mike.
Christine is up in deer park.
some sort of safe zone for now.
Girls are with her.
Why don't you take a break?
I-I got it. No. no.
I'm not gonna sit around
my cabin staring at the walls.
This is where I need to be.
Sir. we have a fire order.
It came across all channels.
but it's garbled.
They cannot authenticate.
Lieutenant? Siegle: Confirmed fire
order. sir. but the target's unclear.
Vampire. vampire. vampire!
Missile incoming high and fast.
Spin four tomahawks.
Hold for a target location.
These coordinates
don't make any sense.
Mason: No response from command.
E.C.O.. aye. Break.
Mml. align four echo missiles.
And place them
in the reload pool.
Do we have a target I.D.?
Now five-one and trail.
Woman: Missile fired from a surface
ship in the north atlantic.
Man: Ballistic missile traveling
at 9.700 miles per hour.
Confirmed. We have
a nuclear burn in the air.
We have no chance to intercept.
Man: Batten down.
Officer at the one.
seal the ship.
Prepare for nuclear detonation.
This is no drill.
Sir. the missile overshot us.
Headed for land.
Detonation in 12 seconds.
Bridge. shield your eyes.
God help us.
Give me a status report on
the switchboard and generators.
Who's that? Chung. sir.
Anyone hurt? No. sir.
What's our engine status?
Sir. the. uh. electromagnetic
pulse from the bomb.
Blew our grid.
Engines won't spin.
No propulsion.
Emergency lights operating
on battery power.
Jeter: Captain!
That you. master chief?
Commo says the radios are down.
No way to get messages
in or out.
We need to move this ship
away from the blast zone.
Lieutenant. let's get
those engines back online.
Yes. sir.
What temperature are we at?
41 degrees. and we've lost
negative pressure.
Damn it.
We're gonna lose everything.
Okay. get the ice.
Fuses in.
Open valves three. four.
and five.
Shut valve to auxiliary engines
and emergency air.
Fuel lever on start.
All right. Give it a kick start.
Sir. we only have one more fuse.
The jet stream's pushing
everything north-northeast.
We got a cloud of radiation
about to drop right on us.
Give it to me.
Sir. it won't hold. It'll hold.
Captain. let somebody else do this.
Rip it.
Get your hand out of there.
You heard me.
Captain. don't. I said rip it!
Badass. captain.
Badass.
Alisha: All engines ahead full.
Left full rudder.
Steady on new course 270.
What's our fuel percentage?
11%. sir.
Even at max conserve.
we'll run dry in six hours.
Any contacts on surface search?
No. sir. 30-mile range.
What is that in the radar shadow?
Change range scale.
Looks like a ship.
Calculate a course to intercept.
Man: Markings indicate
the ship is italian.
Bridge to bridge operational?
I think so. sir.
Vessel in vicinity 48 degrees
north. 15 degrees west.
This is u.S. Navy warship 151
on your starboard bow.
Acknowledge
and identify yourself. Over.
Smith. rowler. benz. green.
you're on provisions.
Master chief. you'll assist
chung with the unrep.
We get as much food and fuel
as we can and we get out.
Let's move.
Rachel: Remember. if the ship
has been impacted by the virus.
It's airborne
and highly. highly contagious.
Even from
a recently deceased corpse.
You must keep your helmets on
at all times.
You trained for this.
You can do it.
Chandler: Lieutenant. send
naval warfare to the kitchen.
Get as much food and supplies
as you can.
We got the stock rooms.
Benzo and I will take
the starboard side.
Make our way to the galley.
Master chief. get that fuel line
across and pump it.
Sending the pull line.
Sending over the hose.
Feed the line.
Engineering. bridge.
Engage fueling.
System online! Commence fueling!
Ship's clear.
No one alive.
commander chandler. Over.
Man: Aiutami.
Aiutami.
Dr. Scott!
He wants help.
The only thing that can
help him now is morphine.
Let go.
Oh. shit!
Frankie!
Put your mask on!
No! It's off!
Oh. shit.
Frankie. Hey.
Frankie! It's all right!
Look! Get up!
Get away. man. Get away!
Master chief.
we're running dry here.
Engineering. bridge. Disengage.
Yes. sir.
They've got it. mr. Chung.
Let's get out of here. Yes. sir.
Danny: You're gonna be fine!
Frankie: Get away!
Just take the food and go get
the hell out of here. No!
I'm not leaving you. frankie!
I'm a dead man.
Just get out of here.
No. man. I'm not leaving you!
You tell him.
He's been exposed.
We put him back in his suit.
And we quarantine him
on the ship!
You can't risk it. sir.
Mission comes first.
I'm not all too interested
in dying like these people.
Give me the gun. sailor.
Frankie. don't be stupid.
I am giving you a direct order!
Put down that weapon!
Frankie. no!
Jeter: Lord god.
by the power of your word.
You stilled the chaos
of the primeval seas.
Made the raging waters
of the flood subside.
And calmed the storm
on the sea of galilee.
As we commit our brother
franklin edward benz to the sea.
Grant him peace and tranquility.
Until that day when franklin
and all those who believe in you.
Will be raised
to the glory of new life.
Promised in the waters
of baptism.
Amen.
Man: Left face!
Present arms!
Ready.
Aim.
Fire!
Ready.
These people depend on me.
I'm in uncharted territory here.
We all are.
Not you. You saw this coming.
I never thought
it would spread so fast.
But now I know why it did.
I compared the blood
that we took from the italian.
To some samples I took
before we left.
The virus has an extra gene now.
Which could have only been added
with human intervention.
So it was weaponized.
Maybe.
Or maybe it escaped
from a lab somehow.
But I think I know
how to stop it.
All the virus cares about
is replicating.
The engineered version
lets it do that unchecked.
So it no longer needs to mutate.
Which makes it stable and easier
to defeat with a vaccine.
Then why hasn't anybody
done that yet?
Because they didn't have
the primordial sample.
We do.
Bridge. commo.
get me the captain.
Sir. we finally
got the comms up.
This came through.
A message from potus.
This is five days old.
Yes. sir. It was transmitted
while the radios were down.
We need to confirm these orders.
Get me the pentagon.
Sir. I've... I've been trying.
but there's no answer.
I'll try the lab.
Get me the presidential bunker.
North carolina's not safe.
President wants us
to change course for mayport.
There's a lab in jacksonville
that's supposed to be secure.
There's no answer there
or the pentagon.
Sir. nothing from the bunker.
Maybe our signal's
not getting out.
We check the transmit side?
That's not the problem.
Their phones are ringing.
Sir. I have another message
coming through!
It was transmitted
at the same time as potus'.
It looks like
a much bigger file.
It's an mpeg. sir. Play it.
Tom.
We're at your father's cabin.
He thinks he has a way
to get this message out.
Through his contacts
at the pentagon.
I have no idea when you
might be seeing this.
Or where you are.
We're all healthy.
We managed to get out early.
And have been up here
for a couple months already.
We haven't heard anything
from your brother or sister.
For a while.
My. um...
My sister didn't make it.
But. honey. we're fine.
We really are.
And I really hope
that you are. too.
Kids!
Come on out here.
It's a tape for dad.
Come on. Come. Come say hi.
Daddy. where are you?
We miss you.
Sam: We love you. daddy.
Just get here if you can.
We love you so much.
Okay. All right.
Let's turn it off.
Hey.
I don't know
what we're going home to.
No radiation detected
within a 100-mile radius. sir.
If america was nuked.
it wasn't here.
We're home.
You said you have what it takes
to make the vaccine.
If you had to. could you do it
here on the ship?
The lab wasn't built for that.
It's for collecting data.
But if you had to. could you?
The expeditionary team
will forward deploy.
And secure the area
for the next group.
Hopefully we'll find support.
Got to be prepared for anything.
Everyone carries
their own biohazard suit.
We do not engage
unless we are engaged.
Prepare your people
and await further orders.
Dismissed.
There's still no answer
from potus.
And nothing from mayport
or the lab.
We can't even get
an f.M. Radio signal.
If the power grid's down.
that means everything's down.
We'll know more when
we get boots on the ground.
Mike. we're not going home.
What are you talking about?
The lab's 200 miles inland.
You saw the news footage.
We'll fight our way in there
if we have to.
And then what?
Generators run out
in a couple weeks.
Maybe the civilian population
tries to overrun it.
There's too many variables.
So. what do we do?
We stay on the ship?
Dr. Scott says she has what she
needs right here. Dr. Scott.
We have standing orders.
From the president
of the United States.
From five days ago.
In the absence
of a command structure.
I decide what's in the best
interest of our mission.
And we have enough food here
to last us what. a week?
How much fuel?
We'll find what we need.
We'll die out there.
No. We will not.
Tom. I appreciate
what you're trying to do.
But it's not gonna work.
People want to get home.
And who exactly gets to go home.
When we have 80 biohazard suits
for 216 people?
We draw lots.
I can't think like that. mike.
It'll at least
give people a chance.
To get back to their families.
to say goodbye.
I'm not letting anybody
on this ship give up.
That's not your call.
You don't get to play god.
I'm still the captain
of this ship.
Now. I've laid out our mission.
I expect you to fall in line.
Rios: Captain's on the bridge.
Left full rudder.
All engines ahead flank.
Sir?
Left full rudder.
All engines ahead flank.
Aye. aye. Left full rudder.
Left full rudder.
All engines ahead flank. aye.
This is the captain speaking.
We have no contact with home.
And I have good reason
to believe.
That the american government
is no longer functioning.
The country we all hoped we were
coming back to no longer exists.
We left these shores
four months ago.
As members
of the United States navy.
But now we are more than that.
Now our duty
is to the entire world.
On board this ship
is the hope...
For our futures.
for our families.
And for all of humanity.
Because in that lab
in our helo bay.
Are the ingredients for a cure.
And this is the safest place
on earth.
For our scientists
to do their work...
On a $3 billion
piece of machinery.
Protected by 216 sailors
in the u.S. Navy.
Our mission now is simple.
We do whatever it takes
to stay alive at sea.
Until they find that cure.
There's an unmanned
food and fuel station.
Outside guantanamo bay.
For the moment.
that is our destination.
We've lost so much already.
But this is the most courageous
and resilient crew.
With whom I have ever
been privileged to serve.
We will come through this
together.
And we will prevail.
Carry on.
Attention on deck.
Lieutenant granderson.
Permission to salute
the captain.
Permission granted.
Hand salute!